explorable.com 2019-11-29

# Privacy Policy

We at explorable.com strive to maintain the highest standards of decency, fairness and integrity in all our operations. Likewise, we are dedicated to protecting our online visitors' privacy on our website.

## Personal Information

Explorable.com collects personally identifiable information from the visitors to our website only on a voluntary basis. Personal information collected on a voluntary basis may include name, postal address, email address, company name and telephone number.

This information is collected if you request information from us or request some other service or information from us. The information collected is internally reviewed, used to improve the content of our website, notify our visitors of updates, and respond to visitor inquiries.

Once information is reviewed, it is discarded or stored in our files. If we make material changes in the collection of personally identifiable information we will inform you by placing a notice on our site. Personal information received from any visitor will be used only for internal purposes and will not be sold or provided to third parties.

## Use of Cookies and Web Beacons

We may use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. Cookies are identifiers that are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize the sites pages, or register with any of our site's services, a cookie enables Explorable.com to recall your specific information on subsequent visits.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying your Web browser; however, if you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the site.

A web beacon is a transparent image file used to monitor your journey around a single website or collection of sites. They are also referred to as web bugs and are commonly used by sites that hire third-party services to monitor traffic. They may be used in association with cookies to understand how visitors interact with the pages and content on the pages of a web site.

We may serve third party advertisements that use cookies and web beacons in the course of ads being served on our web site to ascertain how many times you've seen an advertisement. No personally identifiable information you give us is provided to them for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information on our web site.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/).

Browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is being sent. Privacy software can be used to override web beacons. Taking either of these actions shouldn't cause a problem with our site, should you so choose.

## Children's Online Privacy Protection Act

This website is directed to adults (e.g. students, teachers, parents); it is not directed to children under the age of 13. We operate our site in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, and will not knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under 13 years of age.

## Non-Personal Information

In some cases, we may collect information about you that is not personally identifiable. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. The information collected is used solely for internal review and not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes.

## Release of Information

The personal information about you on explorable.com will never be given away, released or sold, unless there are an informed consent or it is clearly stated or in case of concern about illegal/unethical activities.

However, collective non-identifiable data might be released.

## How You Can Correct or Remove Information

We provide the [terms](https://explorable.com/terms-and-conditions) and our privacy policy as a statement to you of our commitment to protect your personal information. If you have submitted personal information through our website and would like to delete information from our records or would like to update or correct that information, please use our [Contact Us](https://explorable.com/site-contact) page.

This website strives to provide correct information. However, although not intended, we have occasional slips in our content and communication. It might be a sloppy way of saying something, simplifying a phenomenon too much, unintentionally making ourselves misunderstood or just a plain error. We always recommend that you double check our information with other sources as we can not guarantee that everything on the website is correct. If you do find an error, please report it to us on our [contact page](https://explorable.com/site-contact).

## Updates and Effective Dates

Explorable.com reserves the right to make changes in our privacy policy or [terms](https://explorable.com/terms-and-conditions). If there is a material change in our privacy practices, we will indicate on our site that our privacy practices have changed and provide a link to the new privacy policy. We encourage you to periodically review this policy so that you will know what information we collect and how we use it.

## Affiliate links

This website occationally have affiliate links, for example to our books.

## Agreeing to Terms

If you do not agree to explorable.com-[terms](https://explorable.com/terms-and-conditions) or privacy policy as posted here on this website, please do not use this site or any services offered by this site.

Your use of this site indicates acceptance of our terms and our privacy policy.

## General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

At Explorable.com, accessible from [https://Explorable.com](https://explorable.com/), one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by Explorable.com and how we use it.

If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us through email at [info@explorable.com](mailto:info@explorable.com).

We are a Data Controller of your information.

Explorable AS legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Information we collect and the specific context in which we collect the information:

  * Explorable AS needs to perform a contract with you
  * You have given Explorable AS permission to do so
  * Processing your personal information is in Explorable AS legitimate interests
  * Explorable AS needs to comply with the law

Explorable AS will retain your personal information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our policies.

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. If you wish to be informed what Personal Information we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

  * The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you.
  * The right of rectification.
  * The right to object.
  * The right of restriction.
  * The right to data portability
  * The right to withdraw consent

## Log Files

Explorable.com follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services' analytics. The information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movement on the website, and gathering demographic information.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Like any other website, explorable.com uses 'cookies'. These cookies are used to store information including visitors' preferences, and the pages on the website that the visitor accessed or visited. The information is used to optimize the users' experience by customizing our web page content based on visitors' browser type and/or other information.

You can learn how to manage cookies on your web browser by following the [Browser Cookies Guide](https://privacypolicies.com/blog/browser-cookies-guide/).

## Google DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google is one of a third-party vendor on our site. It also uses cookies, known as DART cookies, to serve ads to our site visitors based upon their visit to [www.website.com](http://www.website.com/) and other sites on the internet. However, visitors may choose to decline the use of DART cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network Privacy Policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

## Our Advertising Partners

Some of advertisers on our site may use cookies and web beacons. Our advertising partners are listed below. Each of our advertising partners has their own Privacy Policy for their policies on user data. For easier access, we hyperlinked to some of their Privacy Policies below.

  * Google - <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

  * Ezoic - <https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/explorable.com>

## Privacy Policies

You may consult this list to find the Privacy Policy for each of the advertising partners of Explorable.com.

Third-party ad servers or ad networks uses technologies like cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons that are used in their respective advertisements and links that appear on explorable.com, which are sent directly to users' browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. These technologies are used to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit.

Note that Explorable.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

## Third Party Privacy Policies

Explorable.com's Privacy Policy does not apply to other advertisers or websites. Thus, we are advising you to consult the respective Privacy Policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information. It may include their practices and instructions about how to opt-out of certain options.

You can choose to disable cookies through your individual browser options. To know more detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers, it can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

## Children's Information

Another part of our priority is adding protection for children while using the internet. We encourage parents and guardians to observe, participate in, and/or monitor and guide their online activity.

Explorable.com does not knowingly collect any Personal Identifiable Information from children under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our website, we strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Online Privacy Policy Only

Our Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in Explorable.com. This policy is not applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.

## Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its terms.
